# Ville Hietala

## **Culture Consultant / East Asia Expert**

#### **SUMMARY**

I have a strong passion for learning foreign languages, such as Portuguese and other Romance languages. Korean and Japanese, however, have been my main focuses for several years.

Currently finishing the Master's Program in Linguistic Diversity in the Digital Age.

I am also actively developing my NLP (Natural Language Processing) skills with Python and learning JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, NodeJS and other web development tools.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **University of Helsinki**, Helsinki — BA, East Asian Studies

2011 - 2016

- Korean studies major
- · Minoring linguistics, language technology and sociology

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Inttistore**, Helsinki — Sales Worker

**SEPTEMBER 2016 - MARCH 2017** 

- Sales of clothing, shoes and various military-style equipment in the store
- · Packing and mailing online orders
- Responding to customers' emails and receiving phone calls
- General upkeep of the store and the warehouse

## **Kantar TNS Oy**, Espoo — Telephone Interviewer

**AUGUST 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2016** 

• Interviews in Finnish for research

## Ravintola Torisali Oy, Helsinki— Restaurant Assistant

2012 - 2014

- Providing customers a pleasant restaurant experience
- Bartending and serving

## **Valio Oy**, Toholampi — *Production Worker*

2007, 2009-2010

• Shift work in cheese production

Paraistentie 18 F 48 00280 HELSINKI +358 50 340 1852 villehietala.kr@gmail.com

tenebrae101.github.io linkedin.com/in/villehietala

#### **SKILLS**

Python, R, C#, SQL
HTML, CSS
JavaScript
NLP, NLTK
Google Docs
Adobe Creative Cloud
Video editing, LightWorks
Music production, Cubase
Translation English/Korean
→ Finnish

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Japanese-Language Proficiency Test, N3 2011

"The ability to understand Japanese used in everyday situations to a certain degree."

Google Analytics Individual Qualification 2017

#### **LANGUAGES**

Japanese, Korean, Finnish, English, Finnish, Swedish, Portuguese